kw.com 2019-07-26

# Privacy Policy

### Introduction

We take seriously your awareness and concern about your own personal privacy interests.

This privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") is provided to let you know Keller William Realty International ("Keller Williams") policies and practices regarding its collection and use of your personal data as well as make known your privacy rights that apply to information collected on the Keller Williams website at www.kw.com (the "Site").

By using the Site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, you should discontinue your use of the Site.

### How we collect and use (process) your personal information

KW.com collects data to operate effectively and provide you the best experiences with our headquarters, offices, and associates. 

When you visit the Site, Keller Williams collects information about you and your browsing habits. The information we collect depends on the pages of our website you visit and what you do during your visit.

Keller Williams does not track your online activities over time and across third-party websites in order to provide targeted advertising. 

As with most other websites, Keller Williams website uses cookies to collect session related information (see [KWRI Cookie Policy](https://s3.amazonaws.com/kwuconnect/files/kwconnect.com+-+Cookie+Policy.docx)). To learn more about cookies, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

For most of the browsing services on the Site, Keller Williams does not require your personal information. The data that we may collect can include the following. As mentioned before this depends on the pages of your website that you visit: 

  * **Browsing information.** Name of the domain and host from which you access the internet, the IP address of your computer, the type and version of the browser and operating system that you are using, web log data including the date and time you access our website, and the internet address of the website from which you linked to our site. 
  * **Email information.** Keller Williams may also use "message format" and "message open" sensing technologies to enable Keller Williams to recognize whether you have enabled your email program to receive HTML emails.
  * **Contacts and relationships.** Through the forms that you fill out on this website you may be asked to provide your name, email address, telephone number and address.

Depending on your request other information may also be collected. It is your discretion and determination whether to provide such information.

Additionally, when you use the Site to search for a property, you may be directed to a website operated by a Keller Williams franchisee, and we may provide that Keller Williams office or real estate agent with the information you have provided (e.g. your contact information as provided by you, or the parameters of your search) in addition to information automatically collected about you (e.g. your browser type or operating system version).

### Use of the Information

Keller Williams uses this information to respond to the legitimate interest of your requests, to provide you with information that Keller Williams thinks may be of interest to you, and to operate its business. Keller Williams may disclose your information to its affiliates, agents, and third-party vendors and service providers working on our behalf. Keller Williams has implemented technical measures to protect against the risks of unauthorized access to, erroneous disclosure of, and unlawful interception of Personally Identifiable Information (PII). You should know, however, that Keller Williams cannot fully eliminate such risks. 

Additionally, Keller Williams may disclose part or all of a user’s personal information as required by law, when necessary to protect Keller Williams’s rights or property, or the rights of another user.

Keller Williams may disclose aggregated data and statistics in order to describe the Site to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties. Message format and open sensing technologies are used and allows us to recognize whether you have opened our email messages. We can only detect this if you have enabled your email program to receive HTML emails. 

### Who We Share Your Personal Information With

Keller Williams shares this information with its licensed franchisees, and companies who provide services such as: email marketing, customer relationship management, information storage, data analytics, fraud prevention.

If you use the Site to inquire about a property or contact a real estate agent, broker or office, the information you have provided may be shared with a Keller Williams agent, broker or market center.

We may also disclose your information to law enforcement based on a legal requirement.

### When and how we share information with others

The personal information Keller Williams collects from you is stored in one or more data stores hosted by Keller Williams or third parties located in the United States.

Keller Williams will access your personal data only in regards to Keller Williams and your business needs. Third parties do not have access to your personal information for any other intent other than cloud retrieval and storage. 

### Transferring personal data from the EU to the US

Keller Williams has its headquarters in the United States and the information we collect from you will be processed in the United States. Keller Williams collects and transfers to the U.S. personal data only: with your consent; to perform a contract with you; or to fulfill a compelling legitimate interest of Keller Williams in a manner that does not outweigh your rights and freedoms. Keller Williams strives to apply suitable safeguards to protect the privacy and security of your personal data and to use it only consistent with your relationship with Keller Williams and the practices described in this Privacy Policy. Keller Williams reduces the risk to your rights and freedoms by not collecting or storing sensitive information about you.

**EU-US Privacy Shield Statement:** Keller Williams complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

### Data subject rights

This Privacy Policy is intended to provide you with information about what personal data KW.com collects about you and how it is used. Keller Williams strives to keep your personal data up to date and accurate.

You have the right to access your personal data and receive a copy of your personal data we are processing. You may also request that we delete your data or restrict data that we cannot maintain for a legitimate business need or legal obligation. You may make these types of requests at [DSAR-KWW@kw.com](mailto:DSAR-KWW@kw.com) with the specific access rights request and contact information clearly stated. Requests may be verified with the reported requestor.

You have the right under Privacy Shield to access, correct or delete your personal data.

### Security of your information

To help protect personally identifiable information and the privacy of data that you enter and transmit when using this site, we maintain, technical, physical, and administrative safeguards. We test and update our security technology on an ongoing basis. We train our employees about the importance of the information confidentiality and maintaining the privacy and security of your information.

### Data storage and retention

Your personal data is stored by Keller Williams on its servers, and on the servers of cloud data management providers that Keller Williams uses in the United States. Keller Williams will retain your data for the length of time it is necessary to meet the purposes outlined in this privacy policy, for the duration of your business relationship with Keller Williams, or for as long as legally obligated to do so.

### Underage Customers

This Site is not designed or intended to collect information from children under the age of 13. In addition, Keller Williams does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13.

Keller Williams markets our products and services exclusively to adults. If you are younger than age 18, you may use our website only with the permission and involvement of your parents or guardian.

### Changes and updates to the Privacy Notice

Information privacy is on ongoing responsibility, and we will update this Privacy Policy from time to time as we initiate or update personal data practices and privacy policies.

This Privacy Policy is effective as of the most recent date it was amended. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy for the latest information on our privacy practices.

The last amended/update date is noted at the end of this policy.

### Governing Law

This Privacy Policy is governed by the laws of the State of Texas without giving effect to any principles of conflict of law. All claims arising out of or relating to this Privacy Policy or the Site's Terms of Use will be litigated exclusively in the federal or state courts of Travis County, Texas, USA, and you and Keller Williams consent to personal jurisdiction in those courts.

### Questions, concerns or complaints

If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please email us at [legal@kw.com](mailto:legal@kw.com).

If you do not want to receive e-mail or other mail from Keller Williams, please contact us at [support@kw.com](mailto:support@kw.com).

In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, Keller Williams commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information.

Should you have any questions or complaints about your privacy, please reach out to our privacy team at: [legal@kw.com](mailto:legal@kw.com). You also have the right to make a complaint to your supervisory authority if you are not satisfied with our response to your complaint. 

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 08/10/2018.
